Ghilman Faza

UI/UX Designer | Software Quality Assuarance

% +6285155020756

www.ghilmanfaza.my.id

Sleman, Yogyakarta

Summary

I am a fresh graduate in Informatics with a specialization in UI/UX Design from the Islamic University of Indonesia. Currently, I am interested in learning the role of a manual Software Quality Assurance (SQA) with the hope of bringing a unique design perspective to SQA. With expertise in Design Research and UI/UX Design, I am committed to ensuring top-quality standards for the super app's user interface and experience, contributing to exceptional user satisfaction.

Experience

Bank Syariah Indonesia - Sleman, Special Region Of Yogyakarta

Sep 2023 - Present

Software Quality Assurance

- Top Priority: Security: Maintaining the security of the super app is the top priority, protecting customers' financial data from security threats.
- Effective Defect Reporting: SQA must be able to detect and report application issues with detail and in a timely manner for quick fixes.
- Validation of Quality and User Satisfaction: Ensuring that the super app meets user needs and provides an optimal user experience with a focus on excellent user quality.

Rakamin Academy - South Jakarta, DKI Jakarta.

UI/UX Design Learning Mentor MSIB

Aug 2023 - Present

- Provide guidance and support to aspiring UI/UX designers on design principles, processes, and industry best practices.
- Offer constructive feedback on design projects, helping mentees refine their skills and improve their work.
- Assist mentees in developing their design skills, including wireframing, prototyping, user research, and visual design.
- Conduct regular mentorship sessions, either one-on-one or in a group setting, to address questions, share insights, and discuss design challenges.

DOT Indonesia - Malang, East Java

Feb 2023 - May 2023

UI Designer

- Created design system, wireframes, visual designs, and prototypes using Figma
- Flexible in adapting to every project required and understanding client needs for every given project
- Building relationships with colleagues by conducting meetings twice a week to enhance familiarity and chemistry needed

Alterra Academy X Kampus Merdeka - Malang, East Java

Feb 2022 - Aug 2022

UI/UX Designer

- Learn various UI/UX design materials from basic to advanced stages
- Produce various interfaces from mobile design to web design
- Search and find problems in Inarisk Personal app and redesign them for case studies using the design thinking method
- Create various needs such as userflow, wireframe, low fidelity, high fidelity to prototypes in the form of mobile app designs for users and web app designs in the form of landing pages and dashboards for admins.

Education

Licenses & Certification

Certificate MSIB Kampus Merdeka - Alterra Academy

Aug 2022

Organization

Coordinator Creative Information And Publication Of Laboratory Assistant

Sep 2020 - Oct 2022

Laboratorium Informatika UII

Deputy Coordinator For Supplies, Publications, Decoration And Documentation

Nov 2020 - Mar 2023

Unisi Music Community

Tools & Skills

Mobile Design	Bootstrap	Wireframing	Maze
Web Design	Android Studio	Prototyping	HTML/CSS
UI/UX Design	Figma	Jira	Product Design